Guide to the Norman Hackerman personal and professional papers, 1956-1986 MS 407
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Norman Hackerman personal and professional papers
1956-1986
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hackerman, Norman
MS 407
5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
Professional and personal papers of chemist Dr. Norman Hackerman, the fourth president of Rice University (1970 - 1985), including correspondence, notes for speaking engagements, etc., mainly concerning his membership in the National Science Foundation, National Science Board, and trips to Antarctica.
Biographical Note
Norman Hackerman served as Rice Univerity's fourth President from 1970 - 1985, after serving 25 years at the University of Texas. Immediately preceeding Hackerman was Acting President Frank Vandiver (1969-1970), who succeeded Kenneth Sanborn Pitzer.
During his tenure at Rice, the university launched the Jeese H. Jones Graduate School of Administration, and the Shepherd School of Music, as well as establishing separate engineering and social sciences schools, and new biochemistry, linguistics, and computer science departments. The endowment was significantly increased by his fundraising efforts, and the residential college system went co-ed under his approval.
Controversy touched his presidency in the early 1980s, when Rice hired Watson Brown as head football coach at a high salary, bringing many complaints from academic-oriented students and faculty. Hackerman reportedly considered the criticism a "commentary on society, not on [himself]".
Hackerman, a chemist, was born in Baltimore, MD in 1912, and graduated with bachelor's (1932) and doctoral (1935) degrees from Johns Hopkins University. He joined the University of Texas faculty as an assistant professor in 1945, and worked his way up through the academic ladder to become President in 1967.
Scope and Contents
Professional and personal papers of chemist Dr. Norman Hackerman, the fourth president of Rice University (1970 - 1985), including correspondence, notes for speaking engagements, mainly concerning his membership in the National Science Foundation, National Science Board, and trips to Antarctica.
NOTE: Appointment books and itineraries, which contain a mixture of Rice-related and non-Rice-related entries, have been transfered to the Hackerman Presidential Papers (Boxes 125-128).
Access Restriction
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Dr. Norman Hackerman and Information Services, 1985 and 1986.
Arrangement
This material remains in the original order created and maintained by Dr. Hackerman. The files are arranged alphabetically and include correspondence, notes, and travel information.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Chemists; Universities and colleges -- Archives
Document Types
corrrespondence; notes; calendars
Subjects (Persons)
Hackerman, Norman
Subjects (Corporations)
National Science Foundation (U.S.); National Science Board (U.S.)
- Series I: Alphabetical files A-L
  - A--General correspondence (Aug. 1977-Apr. 1983) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Achievement Rewards for College Scientists (Mar. 1983- Feb. 1984) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Chemical Society (Mar. 1956-May 1985) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Chemical Society. College Chemistry Consultant Service (Oct. 1982-July 1984) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Chemical Society. Committee on Chemistry and Public Affairs (Jan. 1979-Apr. 1983) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Chemical Society. Task Force: Industrial- Academic Cooperation (Aug. 1979-Jan. 1980) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Chemical Society. Task Force: Study of Chemical Education (Apr. 1983-Oct. 1984) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Chemical Society. ACS Award Nominations (June 1967-Oct. 1968) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Institute of Chemists (Sept.-Oct. 1982) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Philosophical Society (Jan. 1981-Sept. 1982) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B--General correspondence (May 1974-Feb. 1985) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bipartisan Budget Appeal (Dec. 1982-Feb. 1984) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C--General correspondence (July 1977-June 1984) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - D--General correspondence (Aug. 1977-Oct. 1984) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - E--General correspondence (July 1977-June 1984) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Electric Power Research Institute (July 1980-Jan. 1981) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Energy Research Advisory Board. University Program Panel--Correspondence (Apr. 1983-Feb. 1984) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Energy Research and Development Administration. CO2 Study Group (Dec. 1976-Dec. 1979) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - F--General correspondence (Apr. 1977-June 1984) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Federation for the Advancement of Freedom in Growing Older (July-Aug. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - G--General correspondence (Jan. 1978-Apr. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gordon Research Conference (May-Nov. 1978) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - H--General correspondence (Aug. 1977-Dec. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Houston Museum of Natural Science (Oct. 1980-Mar. 1981) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - International Insurance Seminars (Aug.-Dec. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - J--General correspondence (Sept. 1977-Sept. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - K--General correspondence (July 1977-Dec. 1983) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - L--General correspondence (Aug. 1977-July 1984) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory (Aug. 1977-Nov. 1978) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series II: Alphabetical Files M-Z
  - M--General correspondence (Jan. 1977-Mar. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. MIT Corporation Visiting Committee for the Department of Chemistry (July 1981-July 1984) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - N--General correspondence (Sept. 1978-June 1983) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Mar. 1981-Jan. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Committee on Government and Higher Education (Jan.-May 1981) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (Mar. 1976-July 1983) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Frank Press Luncheon (Dec. 1984-Mar. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Regional Meeting (Mar. 1983-Jan. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - National Research Council (Jan. 1980-Feb. 1982) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Research Council. Committee on NASA Program Changes (Aug. 1981-Aug. 1982) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - National Research Council. Committee on NASA Scientific and Technological Program Reviews (Nov. 1982-Jan. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - National Research Council. Panel To Review NASA's Numerical Aerodynamics Simulation Program (Aug. 1983-Jan. 1984) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - National Science Board (Feb. 1970-Dec. 1973) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Science Board (Feb. 1970-Dec. 1973) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Science Board (Jan.-Dec. 1975) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Science Board (Jan. 1976-June 1981) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Science Board. Alan T. Waterman Award (Dec. 1975-Dec. 1979) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - National Science Board. Annual Report (Aug. 1976-Feb. 1980) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Science Board. Antarctic Expedition (Jan. 1975-Feb. 1980) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - National Science Board--Board Organization (June 1968- Mar. 1977) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - National Science Board--Board Report 5 (Sept. 1971- Aug. 1976) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National Science Board--Board Report 6 (Aug. 1974) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - National Science Board--Board Report 7 (July 1975-July 1976) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - National Science Board--Board Report 8 (Feb. 1974-June 1975) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - National Science Board--Board Report 9 (Apr. 1976-Mar. 1977) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - National Science Board--Forums (Aug. 1976-Nov. 1979) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - National Science Board--Hackerman--Reappointment (May 1974-Feb. 1980) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - National Science Board--Hackerman--Termination (July 1974-May 1980) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - National Science Board--International Science Activities (July-Nov. 1976) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - National Science Board--O-Tolidine (Aug. 1977) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Science Board--President of U.S. (Feb. 1972- June 1979) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - National Science Board--Speeches and Congressional Testimony (Feb. 1975-Jan. 1980) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - National Science Board--Twenty-fifth Anniversary (Oct. 1974-May 1975) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - National Science Board. Basic Research Committee (Sept. 1975-Apr. 1977) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Science Board. Budget Committee (Feb. 1977- Aug. 1979) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Science Board. Deep Sea and Ocean Margin Drilling Programs Committee (Dec. 1978-Oct. 1979) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - National Science Board. Executive Committee (May 1979) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - National Science Board. House Peer Review Committee (Sept. 1975-Aug. 1977) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - National Science Board. Minorities and Women Committee (May 1977-Dec. 1978) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - National Science Board. Planning and Policy Committee (Mar. 1977-Feb. 1980) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - National Science Board. Programs Committee-- Miscellaneous (Jan. 1971-Sept. 1973) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - National Science Board. Programs Committee--Rann projects (Feb. 1972-Jan. 1974) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - National Science Foundation (Mar. 1962-May 1981) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - National Science Foundation. Office of Polar Programs (July-Aug. 1975) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - National Science Foundation. Science Indicators, 1978 (Dec. 1976-Oct. 1979) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - O--General correspondence (Oct. 1977-May 1984) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - P--General correspondence (June 1977-Mar. 1985) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Philosophical Society of Texas (Dec. 1979-Oct. 1980) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Philosophical Society of Texas--December 1984 Program (Apr.-Dec. 1984) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - R--General correspondence (Sept. 1977-Oct. 1984) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - S--General correspondence (June 1977-Mar. 1985) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Solar Energy Research Institute (Apr. 1978-Apr. 1985) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Speaking Engagements--Calendar (Aug. 1970-Apr. 1986) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Speaking Engagements--Notes (Jan. 1958-Dec. 1969) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Speaking Engagements--Notes (Jan. 1970-Dec. 1979) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - T--General correspondence (June 1977-Nov. 1984) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Texas Energy and Natural Resources Advisory Commission. Advisory Committee on Solar Energy (Oct. 1979-Sept. 1983) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Texas Aerospace and National Defense Technology Development Council (Nov. 1981-Aug. 1982) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Travel Schedules (Sept. 1962-Jan. 1981) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - U--General correspondence (Feb. 1978-May 1982) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - United States. Antarctic Research Program (June 1975- Jan. 1980) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - University of Texas at Austin (Oct. 1970-Feb. 1971) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - University of Texas at Dallas. Chemistry Advisory Panel (Feb. 1983-Apr. 1984) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - V--General correspondence (July 1977-Feb. 1982) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - W--General correspondence (Sept. 1977-Mar. 1985) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - White House Conference on Science and Technology-- Proposal (June 1978) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series III: Speeches
  - Town and Gown, 12-63 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Conference of Southwest Foundations; Albuquerque, NM, 4-9-64 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 16th Annual Conference of Southwest Foundations; Albuquerque, NM, 4-10-64 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Texas Tech College Chapter of Phi Kappa Phi, 5-7-64 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Florida Atlantic University Commencement; Boca Raton, FL, 8-14-65 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Symposium of Regional Development of Graduate Education in the Southwest; Austin, TX, 3-17-66 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - HC Symposium; Houston, TX, 4-13-66 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Texas Lutheran College Honors Day; Seguin, TX, 5-3-67 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Law Day; Ft. Worth, TX, 5-1-68 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 2nd Marine Sciences Business Potentials Conference; Corpus Christi, TX, 9-26-68 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - American Petroleum Institute; Chicago, IL, 11-12-68 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - FSU, SE-ACS; 12-6-68 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Metropolitan Dinner Club; Ft. Worth, TX, 1-15-70 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Southwest Texas State University, Inauguration of Dr. B.M. Jones; 2-14-70 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - American Chemical Society, Sargent-Welch Award Symposium; Houston, TX, 2-24-70 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - ICUCE; 3-70 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - International Ex-Students Conference; Austin, TX, 5-13-70 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-25-70 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Society of Rice University Women; Houston, TX, 9-16-70 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Houston Philosophical Society; Houston, TX, 9-17-70 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Rice University Homecoming; Houston, TX, 10-3-70 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 10-20-70 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society; Houston, TX, 10-22-70 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 32nd Management Conference; 10-70 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Rice [University] Faculty Women's Club; Houston, TX, 11-11-70 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - AAAS; Chicago, IL, 12-30-70 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Rice University Majors Day Opening; Houston, TX, 2-3-71 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Houston High School Counselors; Houston, TX, 2-3-71 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Rice University Fund Alumni; Houston, TX, 2-9-71 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Rice University Alumni-Parents; Dallas, Beaumont, Houston, TX, 3-8-71, 3-9-71, 3-13-71 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - University of Houston Commencement; Houston, TX, 5-15-71 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - DC Alumni; Washington, DC, 5-19-71 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Jesse Jones High School Commencement; Houston, TX, 6-2-71 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - West Berlin Seminar; Germany, 6-21-71 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-24-71 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Rice University Picnic; Houston, TX, 9-19-71 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Rice University Inauguration; Houston, TX, 9-24-71 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 10-18-71 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Southern Association of Colleges Schools Conference of Academic Deans; 11-30-71 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - House of Representatives Appropriation Committee; Washington, DC, 2-29-72 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 3-11-72, 3-31-73 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - University of Texas Honors Day; Austin, TX, 4-8-72 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 4-28-72 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Texas A (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 5-20-72 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Rice University New York Alumni; 5-23-72 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Bellaire High School Commencement; Houston, TX, 5-25-72 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - St. Edwards University Commencement; Austin, TX, 5-27-72 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 7-13-72 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Rice University Faculty Forum; Houston, TX, 8-18-72 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-22-72 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Rice University Engineering Council; Houston, TX, 10-25-72 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 10-26-72 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Rice University Boston Alumni; Boston, MA, 11-8-72 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 11-10-72 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Tri-Services Corrosion Conference; Houston, TX, 12-6-72 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Rice University Faculty Forum; Houston, TX, 12-7-72 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Rice University Alumni; 1972 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Rice University Faculty Forum; Houston, TX, 1-12-73 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 1-22-73 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 1-30-73 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Rice University Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy; Houston, TX, 2-12-73 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 5-3-73 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 5-4-73 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-21-73 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 9-12-73 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 9-17-73 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - TEG Officers; Houston, TX, 10-5-73 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 11-5-73 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Rice University Football Banquet; Houston, TX, 11-73 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Rice University Alumni; 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 4-17-74 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - SACS Site Visit; Houston, TX, 4-21-74 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges Council of Deans; Phoenix, AZ, 4-25-74 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Rotary Club; Houston, TX, 5-30-74 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Rice-Baylor Cooperation; 8-13-74 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Rice University Foreign Students; Houston, TX, 8-19-74, 8-16-76 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-20-74 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 9-3-74 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Hanszen College Opening; Houston, TX, 9-12-74 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Society of Rice University Women; Houston, TX, 9-16-74 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Rice University El Paso/Tulsa/Pittsburgh/Dallas Alumni/Society of Rice University Women, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX; 2-3-75 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - American Institute of Mechanical Engineers; New York, NY, 2-17-75 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Masterson Texana Collection Opening; Houston, TX, 3-2-75 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Rice University Faculty; Houston, TX, 3-24-75 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 4-2-75 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Rice [University] Associates; Houston, TX, 4-10-75 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 4-12-75 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 5-10-75 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Rice University Tulsa Alumni; 6-6-75 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-19-75 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Shepherd School Inaugural Festival; Houston, TX, 9-19-75 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 9-23-75 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 9-25-75 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - AAUP; 9-75 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dedication of George R. Brown School of Engineering; Houston, TX, 11-12-75 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Rice [University] Associates; Houston, TX, 1-15-76 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Rice University Faculty Forum; Houston, TX, 2-15-76 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Rice University Student Convocation; Houston, TX, 2-76 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 3-27-76 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 4-9-76 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Rice University Engineering Alumni; 4-13-76 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting; Houston, TX, 5-2-76 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-17-76 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 10-2-76 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - International Council on Swedish Industry; 1976 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Rice University Alumni/Development Meetings; 1976-77 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Rice University Engineering Alumni; 3-15-77 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - 2-Year College Chemistry Conference; Wilmington, DE, 4-22-77 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - NSF/RANN Conference on Research in Excavation Technology; Houston, TX, 4-26-77 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Rice University Commencement; Houston, TX, 5-14-77 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-23-77 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 8-27-77 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Rice University Homecoming Banquet; Houston, TX, 10-29-77 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Rice University Student Meeting; Houston, TX, 11-14-77 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Rice University Associates; 3-30-78 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Rice [University] ROTC Presidential Review; Houston, TX, 4-26-78 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Jones Opening; 5-2-78 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-22-78 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Rice University Faculty; Houston, TX, fall 1978 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-21-79 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Rice University Fund Kickoff; Houston, TX, 8-28-79 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 11-2-79 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 3-15-80 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - IEEE Awards Luncheon; San Antonio, TX, 4-22-80 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-18-80 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 11-8-80 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 3-14-81 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-19-81 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Rice University Fund Kickoff; Houston, TX, 9-2-81 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 10-23-81 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-17-82 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Rice University Fund Kickoff; Houston, TX, 9-1-82 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 10-15-82 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Rice University Associates; Houston, TX, 3-29-83 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Kiwanis Club; Houston, TX, 3-30-83 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-23-83 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Rice University Fund; Houston, TX, 9-6-83 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Rice University Alumni Executive Committee; Houston, TX, 10-13-83 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Rice University Parent's Day; Houston, TX, 3-17-84 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Rice University Associates; Houston, TX, 3-21-84 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Julian Huxley Papers Opening; Houston, TX, 3-84 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 5-11-84 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Rice University Engineering Advisory Council; Houston, TX, 6-22-84 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Pasadena Rotary Club; Pasadena, TX, 7-27-84 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Rice University Matriculation; Houston, TX, 8-21-84 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Dedication of 45, 90, 180; Houston, TX, 1-24-85 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Rice University ROTC Presidential Review; Houston, TX, 4-24-85 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Rice University Convocation; Houston, TX, 4-29-85 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Rice University Fund Council; Houston, TX, 5-10-85 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Rice University Board of Trustees; Houston, TX, 5-24-85 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Rice University President's Executive Luncheon; Houston, TX, 5-30-85 (Box 9, Folder 23 "Impact on Commerce in Space on Education," n.d.)
  - "Impact on Commerce in Space on Education," n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Council of Graduate Schools Annual Meeting; Williamsburg, VA, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - International Colleges Universities Conference; Atlantic City, NJ, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Introduction of Lt. Gov. Ben Barnes; n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, unidentified, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Speech correspondence (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Business files
  - Correspondence, general (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #1: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #2: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #3: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #4: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #5: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Corrosion Monographs Series #6: editorial corresp. (Box 10, Folder 6)